We're going to start the OTA update section by defining a few status definitions pertaining to whether
the update is pending, successful or it's failed, and our JavaScript function for getting the status
is already prepared for reacting to these statuses.
So let's head over to the jazz file and take a look.
And here in the good state is function, it says if Flushing was complete, the status is one else,
it's a negative one.
And here we have the successful situation.
And the unsuccessful situation is right here.
OK, so we need to send the statuses accordingly on the web server side so that this JavaScript function
reacts in the appropriate manner.
So let's head over to the head of file now.
And here will define OTA update pending.
As zero.
And then define.
OTA update successful.
As one.
And now let's define OTA update failed.
As negative one.
Also, we actually don't need the less enum status here, so let's get rid of it.
And in the C file, let's remove the case for it as well.
OK, so now back to the head of file.
Let's define a timer callback function.
Which calls ESP restart upon successful firmware update.
And here will say firmware update, reset, call back.
And it takes a void pointer argument.
OK.
And let's actually name it properly at the HTP server to it.
OK, that's better.
Now we'll head over to the see file.
And include.
ESP to upstage.
And that's for OTA functions.
And also include this slash program, Dot H.
And that's for our men macro.
And then we want to create a global variable for firmware updates status.
Which is a static int in call it global underscore firmware, underscore update, underscore status
and set it to OTA update pending.
And now let's copy this variable, and let's bring it to the monitor under OTA update successful.
And let's set it to OTA update successful.
OK.
And then under OTA update failed, let's set it to OTA update failed.
So now in the US, let's see what handlers we need to define.
Within update firmware.
We have a post for OTA update.
OK.
And when the Web page is accessed, get update status is called.
And there we have the forgotten status.
And that's also a post method.
So here we have to post methods OTA update and OTA status to be handled.
So let's go back to the C file.
And down to our you or I handlers.
All right, so here, let's register.
OTA update handler.
And we need an instance of the euro, a structure and call it to underscore update.
And the you are right.
Will be forward slash OTA update.
And the method will be a top post.
And the handler will call HTTP server OTA update handler.
And we can set the user to know.
OK.
And then call FTPd, register you or a handler in pest to handle.
And then a reference to the OTA update struct.
OK.
Now will register the status handler.
And call it a status.
And for that, you are right, that will be forward slash OTA status.
And then the method will be http post as well.
And the handler.
We'll call HTP server, OTA status handler.
User CTCs is now.
And then we'll register the handler.
Pass the handle and a reference to the otter struct.
OK, next, let's define the OTA update handler.
And let's make a comment here, receives the bin file.
Via the Web page and handles the firmware update.
And the parameter R e q is the HTTP request for which the you are right needs to be handled.
And the return is OK.
Otherwise, PSG fail if time out occurs and the update cannot be started.
And the return is ISP error type, and it's our OTA update handler, which takes a pointer to the HTTP
the request type, and it's RFQ.
And here we need an instance of the ELISpot handle structure.
And we'll call it Otere Handle.
And next, we need a buffer to hold data received from the Web page, so say Char a buffer and it's
1024 bytes.
And also, we need a variable to hold the content length.
So say, into content length.
Equals the request content length, and we can access that like so.
And also, we need to track the content received.
And set it to zero.
And let's add another variable to receive data from each HTP request function, call and call it and
to receive length.
And also, we need a variable to tell us when the actual firmware update file content is found.
So we'll say Bull is request, but started.
And set it to false.
And also, we need to check the flesh status, so-called this one flesh successful and set it to false.
OK, now we need an instance of the ESP partition struct, and that's a pointer to a constant ESG partition
type.
And call it update partition.
Which equals the result of ESPN to get next update partition.
And the parameter is no.
OK.
And if we follow this function.
We can see that it returns the next OTA application partition, which should be written with new firmware
and to call this function to find an OTA application partition, which can be passed to SPRO to begin.
So next, let's create a do while loop to receive the update file.
And it's while received length.
Is greater than zero and content received.
It's less than content length.
OK.
And the first thing we'll do here is read the data for the request.
And say, if receive length.
Equals HTTP requests receive.
And the first parameter is Ari.
Q The second is a buffer.
And the third is the minimum between the content length.
And the size of a buffer.
And if this result is less than zero.
Then we need to handle the timeout error case here.
So let's say check if timeout occurred.
And then we'll be right if received length.
Is httpd suck it air time out?
Then we will lug a message.
That the OTA update handle the function.
Has experienced a socket timeout.
And then, let's say continue.
And we'll come and retry receiving if time out occurred.
Otherwise we can log a message.
That there was some other error.
So we'll say that the OTA update handler, the experienced OTA other error.
And we can actually print the received length.
OK, so then at this point, we can return ESP fail.
All right, so now we can continue.
And here let's print.
Let's print that the OTA update handler has received some bytes of the content.
And we'll give it the content received in the content length.
All right, and then we can check.
Is this the first data we are receiving?
If so.
It will have the information in the header that we need.
And first of all, say if the request body is not started.
Then we'll set request body started to true.
And then we'll come here and get the location of the -- content.
Meaning will remove the Web form data from the request.
OK, so now let's say cha point to body start underscore P equals string string of the Otere buffer.
And we need to find these slash or slash and slash or slash and.
And then increment to point two by four.
For the length of the slash or slash ends.
All right, so now we'll get the entire body part length.
From the received length.
Minus the difference between the body start point to.
And the beginning of the Otay buffer.
OK, so here we needed to get the body start point to to point to the beginning of the data that we
want without the web form junk data.
And we also need the length of data that we want so that we can pass this information to spot a right
and we'll do that later.
OK, so next, let's print some information.
About the OTA file size so that it shows up while we are receiving the file.
And give it the content length.
And then here we can say ESP error type error.
Equals ESP to begin.
And give it the update partition and then the file size is.
Size unknown.
And then give a reference to the yacht to handle.
OK, then we'll say if error is not equal to ESP, OK?
Then print that there was an error.
And we'll say air with OK to begin.
Cancelling OTA.
OK, then return, ESB fail.
All right, then we'll say else.
And then we'll print that we're writing to politicians subtype.
Will say writing to politicians subtype.
Offset.
And give the update partition subtype.
And the update partition address.
So now let's say.
Right, this first part.
Of the data.
And say the spot, right?
Then pass the to handle.
The body start point to.
And the body part length.
And then we'll say else.
In the case that the body data has already been found and it's not the first part of the data that we've
received and written with spot, right, and then we want to write a data.
So let's comment.
Right.
A data.
And we'll use SBO to write.
And then pass the yacht handle and give it the yacht a buffer this time.
And we want the received length this time.
And now we want to increment the content received.
By the received length.
So we are going to do this while the received length is greater than zero.
And the content received is less than the content length as we're incrementing the content received
with each call to receive data.
So once that's done, we can say if the spot end.
In pass the handle.
And if that returns, ESP, OK.
Then let's update the partition.
And right, if he spoke to set boot partition and give it the update partition.
If that is ESP, OK?
Then the Konst ESP partition type.
Pointer boot partition.
Equals the spot to get boot partition.
And now let's log information that about the next boot partition.
And say next boot partition subtype.
Is that offset?
And then give the boot partition subtype.
And the boot partition address.
OK, then set flesh successful to true.
Else we need to log an error that says fleshed error.
So let's log about this function.
And we'll say fleshed error.
And then if e-sport end didn't go well.
We also have an error.
And that air that's from ESPN and.
OK, and lastly, we want update global variables throughout the file.
So let's send a message about the status.
And we can say, if flesh successful.
And then we could one line this HTTP server monitor send message.
HTP message OTA update successful.
Else.
We'll send the message.
That http message OTA update failed.
All right.
And now we can return ESP, OK?
OK.
Well done, so we have a bit more to do, but I think that's enough time for now.
So let's take a short break and let's continue in the next lesson.